abbyy.com 2019-04-03

# ABBYY Privacy Policy

ABBYY USA Software House, Inc. (“ **ABBYY** ,” “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”) has created this website (the “ **Website** ” or the “ **Site** ”) to provide a platform for sales, registration, and support for ABBYY's character recognition, data capture, linguistics, and translation products and services.

ABBYY is committed to maintaining your privacy.  This Privacy Notice (“ **Privacy Notice** ”) outlines our privacy practices, including the types of information that you may provide to us, how we use such information and the choices you have regarding our use of that information.  We may collect the information through our Website; when you purchase, register or use our products through computers or mobile devices; through our online support services; or through email messages that we send to you (collectively, including all online methods, the “ **Services** ”), or offline, such as when you attend one of our trade shows or contact our customer service line.  Our Privacy Notice applies to (i) casual visitors to our Site, who do not participate in the Services (“ **Site Visitors** ”), (ii) individuals who purchase or register products through the Website or otherwise participate in our Services (“ **Registered Users** ”), (iii) users of our products and (iv) individuals whose information we obtain offline (collectively, including Site Visitors, Registered Users, users of products, and other individuals, “ **you** ”).

## 1\. Notice.

**1.1.  The Types of Information You May Provide.** Information you may provide or that we may collect from you while visiting our Site or while participating in our Services falls into three broad categories: (i) Personally Identifiable Information, (ii) Activities Information, and (iii) Anonymous Information.

**1.2. Personally Identifiable Information.** We use the term **“Personally Identifiable Information”** to mean any information that could reasonably be used to identify you, including your name, address, e-mail address, payment card number, telephone number.

**1.3. Activities Information.** We use the term “ **Activities Information** ” to refer to information collected by so-called “persistent identifiers” such as cookies and web beacons. Unlike Personally Identifiable Information, Activities Information does not directly identify a particular person; the information, however, is or can potentially be linked to a particular computer or device.

**1.4. Anonymous Information.** “ **Anonymous Information** ” is information that does not identify you, and may include statistical information concerning, for example, your use of our products and Services, your access to content on our Website, or the pages on our Site that you visit most frequently.

## 2\. Choice and consent.

We have structured our Website so that you may visit our Site without revealing your identity or providing any Personally Identifiable Information. Please read this Privacy Notice carefully. Providing your Personally Identifiable Information to us through the Services confirms your agreement to be bound by this Privacy Notice.

**2.1. Receiving Electronic Communications from Us.** You can opt-out of receiving bulletins, updates, the ABBYY newsletter, or other marketing-related materials by clicking on the unsubscribe link here, [Unsubscribe](http://promo.abbyy.com/SubscriptionManagement.html), or on the bottom of each Marketing e-mail.

**2.2. This Privacy Notice does not apply to the Xerox Easy Translator Service**

Please be advised that if you elect to opt out as described herein pursuant to this Privacy Notice from receiving marketing email communications and from the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information, **it will not operate to opt you out with respect to the Xerox Easy Translator Service and its associated website**. You are required to separately opt out from receiving marketing email communications and from the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information with respect to the Xerox Easy Translator Service pursuant to the separate Xerox Easy Translator Privacy Notice which may be found [here](https://xeroxtranslates.com/docs/XeroxEasyTranslator_PrivacyNotice_en.pdf).

If you have previously opted out of receiving marketing email communications or from the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information **only** with respect to the Xerox Easy Translator Service and as provided in the Xerox Easy Translator Privacy Notice, please be advised that it will not operate as your opt out election for any other marketing email communicatons or your opt out of sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information with respect to any other products or services offered or supported by ABBYY. **In order to unsubscribe from such other marketing email communications or from the sharing of your Personally Identifiable Information that are unrelated to the Xerox Easy Translator Service, you must do so in accordance with, and as provided in, this Privacy Notice.**

**2.3. Our Sharing of Your Personally Identifiable Information with Affiliates for Their Direct Marketing Purposes.  **If you would prefer that we do not share your Personally Identifiable Information on a going-forward basis with our Affiliates (as defined in Section 7.1 (ABBYY Affiliates)) for their direct marketing purposes, you may opt-out of this sharing by contacting the Privacy Officer as described in Section 16 (Contact Us). If you opt-out from this sharing, you will also automatically opt-out from receiving marketing communications from ABBYY.

**2.4.  Exception for Administrative Messages.** Please understand that if you choose not to receive marketing-related messages from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, such as notices concerning operation of this Website or other Services, products you have purchased, downloaded or registered for, and legal and other related notices concerning your relationship with ABBYY and this Site. You cannot opt-out from receiving administrative messages.

## 3\. Collection.

**3.1.** **Our Collection of Personally Identifiable Information.** We and certain service providers operating on our behalf collect Personally Identifiable Information from you. Personally Identifiable Information may be collected as part of the normal operation of our products and Services, for example, when contained in data that you or we capture, convert or translate using our products or in connection with your use of other features of our Services. The following further explains the Personally Identifiable Information that is collected:

**3.1.1.** **Registration Information.** If you choose to register with us in order to receive technical support, information and discounts on newer versions and updates for our products, and other benefits we may provide, (regardless of whether your purchase was made through ABBYY or one of our resellers or distributors), we will ask you to provide certain Personally Identifiable Information, such as name, email address, telephone number or other information. If you do not register your product with us, we will be unable to provide you with technical support. All information you provide in connection with the registration process is collected by one of our Affiliates and is shared with us.

**3.1.2. Purchase of Products and Services.  **We collect Personally Identifiable Information, including contact information (such as name, email address, and shipping address) and financial information (such as payment card number, expiration date and security code), in connection with your orders and purchases through our Services using a credit or debit card.

**3.1.3. Email Addresses.** Both Site Visitors and Registered Users may wish to provide us with comments and feedback concerning our Site and products generally. By communicating with us for these purposes, you may provide us with your email address and other Personally Identifiable Information.

**3.1.4. Questionnaires and Surveys.** Our Website may allow Site Visitors and Registered Users to participate in surveys and questionnaires, which we may post on the Site from time to time. You are free to choose whether you participate in a survey or questionnaire. We may ask that, in addition to providing your responses, you also provide Personally Identifiable Information. We advise you to use discretion in including any Personally Identifiable Information that would enable a third party reviewing your response to link the response to you.

**3.1.5. Offline.** We may collect Personally Identifiable Information from you offline, such as when you call us seeking customer service or technical support, attend one of our trade shows or place an order over the phone.

**3.1.6. Other Sources.** We may receive your Personally Identifiable Information from other sources, such as public databases, joint marketing partners, social media platforms, data brokers, from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected on social media platforms, as well as from other third parties, including those who provide list enhancement services.

**3.2. Our Collection of Activities Information.** We and certain service providers operating on our behalf collect Activities Information about your activity with respect to our Services. The following further summarizes the Activities Information that is collected:

**3.2.1. IP Addresses; Logs.** ABBYY may automatically receive and record information in our server logs from your browser or device, including your IP address (the Internet address of your computer), your computer's name, the type and version of your web browser, referrer addresses, device manufacturer and model, language, name and version of the Services (such as the app) you are using and other generally-accepted log information. We may also record page views (hit counts) and other general statistical and tracking information.

**3.2.2. Cookies.** A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, which is sent to your browser from a website's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. We may use cookies on our website.

**3.2.3. Click-Throughs.** We may send email messages, which use a “click-through URL” linked to content on our Website. When you click one of these URLs, you pass through our web server before arriving at the destination web page. If you prefer not to be tracked simply do not click text or graphic links in the email.

**3.2.4. Mobile App Usage.** When you download and use one of our products designed for mobile devices (an “ **App** ”), we and our service providers may track and collect App usage data, such as the date and time the App on your device accesses our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the App based on your device number.

**3.3.** **Our Collection of Anonymous Information.** We may collect Anonymous Information through features of the software supporting the Services and use this information as follows:

**3.3.1. Site Visitors.** As indicated above, you may use our Site without registering or submitting any information to us. In that case, the only information we collect from your visit will be Anonymous Information that does not identify you in any way.

**3.3.2. Questionnaires and Surveys.** Our Website may allow Site Visitors and Registered Users to participate in surveys and questionnaires, which we may post on the Site from time to time. You are free to choose whether you participate in a survey or questionnaire.

**3.3.3. Computer Configuration.** We may collect information about your operating system and browser, as well as the presence of any software that our Services may require to operate with your computer or device, or other third party software on your computer or device.

## 4\. Use.

**4.1. Our Use of Personally Identifiable Information.** ABBYY and certain service providers acting our behalf use Personally Identifiable Information for the purposes set out in this Notice. We use Personally Identifiable Information to provide our products and the Services, for example, to provide you document capture, optical character recognition or document conversion functionality, to respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests.

**4.1.1. Registration Information.** Registration information is used by ABBYY for internal purposes in providing our products and the Services. As provided in Section 4.1.3 (Informational Notices and Bulletins; Marketing), we may also use this information to send marketing materials and informational notices.

**4.1.2. Product/Sales Information.** Information collected in connection with purchasing products is used for billing purposes, filling orders, and contacting you in the event that there is an issue with your order. Please note that ABBYY does not directly collect or store your financial account information – instead, we use a third-party payment service (the “ **Payment Processing Company** ”) to collect and process your payment information.

**4.1.3. Informational Notices and Bulletins; Marketing.** Periodically, we may send news, bulletins, marketing materials, or other information to you in the interest of improving our products and services, developing and offering new products and services. Subject to your choice as provided in Section 2 (Choice) above, we will use Personally Identifiable Information to send communications and may share Personally Identifiable Information with ABBYY Affiliates.

**4.1.4. Questionnaires and Surveys.** Survey and questionnaire information may be used by ABBYY for the purposes of monitoring or improving the use and appeal of this Site and our products and Services.

**4.1.5. Administrative Information.** We may send administrative information to you, for example, information regarding the Services and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.

**4.1.6. Other Business Purposes.** We use Personally Identifiable Information for our business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new products, enhancing, improving or modifying our Services, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities.

**4.1.7. Protecting Rights.** We may use Personally Identifiable Information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our Affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our Affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

**4.2. Our Use of Activities Information.** We and certain service providers operating on our behalf use Activities Information about your activity with respect to our Services. In addition, advertisers and other third parties might use Activities Information via our Services. The following further summarizes how the Activities Information is used.

**4.2.1. IP Addresses; Logs.** General statistics and tracking information will be aggregated with that of other users in order to understand how our Website is being used, and for security and monitoring purposes.

**4.2.2. Cookies.** We may use cookies to provide you with a tailored user experience and to make it easier for you to use a website upon a future visit. We use cookies to recognize you when you return to our Website. You may set your browser so that it does not accept cookies. Cookies must be enabled on your web browser, however, if you wish to access certain personalized features of our products and Services.

**4.2.3. Tags.** We may use so-called “pixel tags” — small graphic images (also known as “web beacons” or “single-pixel GIFS”) — to tell us what parts of our website have been visited or to measure the effectiveness of searches customers perform on our Site. Pixel tags also enable us to send email messages in a format customers can read, and they inform us whether emails have been opened, to help ensure that our messages are of interest to our Registered Users.

**4.2.4. Click-Throughs.** We track click-through data to help determine interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you prefer not to be tracked simply do not click text or graphic links in the email.

**4.2.5. Computer Configuration.** We use the information collected about your computer configuration to determine if your computer is compatible with our system.

**4.3. Our Use of Anonymous Information.** We use Anonymous Information to analyze the effectiveness of our Site, to improve our products and Services, and for other similar purposes. In addition, from time to time, we may undertake or commission statistical and other summary analyses of the general behavior and characteristics of users of our products and Services and the characteristics of visitors at our Site, and may share Anonymous Information with third parties, including third party ad service providers or advertisers (“ **Advertisers** ”).

## 5\. Retention and disposal.

We retain Personally Identifiable Information for the period of time needed in order to process your transaction and maintain our customer records. ABBYY has data retention and disposal processes to dispose of Personally Identifiable Information in a manner that is designed to protect against loss, theft, misuse, or unauthorized access. Please note, however, that it may not be technically or commercially feasible to remove this information completely, for example, due to archived backups and records of deletions that are no longer reasonably accessible.

## 6\. Access and correction.

If you would like to review, correct, update, or delete Personally Identifiable Information you have previously provided to ABBYY, please contact us as provided in Section 16 (Contact Us). In your request, please make clear what Personally Identifiable Information you would like to have changed or what other limitations you would like to put on our use of Personally Identifiable Information you have provided to us. We may request information from you for purposes of verifying your identity before fulfilling such requests. While we will try to comply with your requests to delete your Personally Identifiable Information from our databases, please understand that it may not be technically or commercially feasible to remove this information completely. We will try to comply with your requests made in accordance with this section as soon as reasonably practicable.

## 7\. Disclosure to third parties.

We may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information in the following ways:

**7.1. ABBYY Affiliates.** We share information that you provide or that we collect with ABBYY Affiliates (our “ **Affiliates** ”) located worldwide, for all of the purposes described in this Privacy Notice, including, without limitation, for the provision of technical support to you and for marketing purposes. By “Affiliate,” we mean an entity that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with ABBYY, whether the control results from equity ownership, contract, overlapping management, or otherwise.

**7.2. ABBYY Vendors.** We may employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf, such as hosting or maintaining the Website, providing services related to the products and Services, collecting information, responding to and sending electronic mail, or other functions necessary to our business. We may need to share your Personally Identifiable Information with these companies (collectively, “ **Vendors** ”) in order to allow them to perform such functions. We require Vendors not to use your Personally Identifiable Information for any other purpose.

**7.3. Transfer of Assets.** ABBYY may transfer to a third party information it collects, including any Personally Identifiable Information, in connection with a sale or other corporate transaction of all or substantially all of the assets of the business entity responsible for the information under this Notice.

**7.4. Protecting Rights.** ABBYY may disclose Personally Identifiable Information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (c) to enforce our terms and conditions; (d) to protect our operations or those of any of our Affiliates; (e) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our Affiliates, you or others; and (e) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

## 8\. Security.

We have put in place security systems designed to protect against unauthorized access to or disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us, and we take reasonable steps to secure and safeguard this Information. Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us in accordance with Section 16 (Contact Us).

## 9\. Quality / data integrity.

We rely on you to provide us complete and accurate personal information and to contact us if correction of such information is required.

## 10\. Monitoring and enforcement.

ABBYY uses a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this Privacy Notice and periodically verifies that the Privacy Notice is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, and accessible. We encourage users to raise any concerns by contacting us, as provided in Section 16 (Contact Us), and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information.

## 11\. Any information linked with your personally identifiable information is protected as “personally identifiable information.”

To enable us to better understand the characteristics of our users and to provide services tailored to your needs, we may link the Personally Identifiable Information you have provided with Anonymous Information or other information. If we combine or link any Anonymous Information or other information with your Personally Identifiable Information, the resulting combination will be treated and protected as Personally Identifiable Information under this Privacy Notice.

## 12\. Banner ads; advertising profiles.

Our Website may include the use of banner ad partners for the serving and targeting of ads, promotions, and other marketing messages. Ads may be provided, in some cases, by Advertisers. These Advertisers may use traditional banner ads, or other advertising methods, such as advertising using profiles and related Content. An Advertiser may place or utilize its own cookie on your browser, and may use information about your visit to our sites, such as the number of times you have viewed the ad. If the Advertiser requests that you provide to it Personally Identifiable Information, please be aware that this Advertiser's use and collection of this information will be governed by its own Privacy Notice, and not our Privacy Notice. We recommend that you review the Advertiser's Privacy Notice before providing Personally Identifiable Information.

## 13\. Participation by children and teens; advisory.

Due to federal law (as reflected in the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act), YOU MUST BE AT LEAST 13 YEARS OLD TO USE OUR SITE AND SERVICES. IF YOU ARE BETWEEN 13 AND THE APPLICABLE AGE OF MAJORITY, PLEASE REVIEW THIS AGREEMENT WITH YOUR PARENT OR GUARDIAN.

## 14\. Notification of changes.

From time to time, ABBYY may change its Privacy Notice. If we make any material changes we will post the new Privacy Notice at the privacy link on our Website.

## 15\. Relationship to terms of use and other contracts.

This Privacy Notice must be read in conjunction with our Terms and Conditions of Use and the provisions of our Terms and Conditions of Use are incorporated herein. To the extent the Terms and Conditions of Use conflict with the terms of this Privacy Notice, the terms of this Privacy Notice will control. Moreover, to the extent this Privacy Notice conflicts with the terms and conditions of any specific agreement you enter with us, the terms and conditions of such specific agreement will control.

## 16\. Contact us.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Notice, the practices of this Site or our Services, please contact us at:

Privacy Officer  
ABBYY USA Software House, Inc.  
890 Hillview Court, Suite 300, Milpitas, CA 95035​

408-457-9777

## 17\. Effective date.

The effective date of this Privacy Notice is July 22, 2016.

COPYRIGHT AND LEGAL NOTICE. Copyright © 2017 ABBYY. All Rights Reserved.
